Syed Zeeshan Ali (MCS, MCP)

gecezeeshan@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/zeeshan-ali-4b027918/

Profile

Software development team manager with over 13+ years of experience in all phases of SDLC, focusing on conceptualizing business needs and translating them into viable technical solutions. Strengths include successful analysis and problem-solving expertise, highly rated oral and written communications skills, and proven project management experience. Strong background in Microsoft Technology development environment has provided the opportunity to work on a diversity of software projects, especially focusing on database analysis and design. Sound in managing and implementing DEVOPS operations using azure platform. Good work ethics with excellent communication and interpersonal skills.

Experience

DEVELOPMENT MANAGER | CONTOUR SOFTWARE | SEPTEMBER 2014 - PRESENT

My responsibilities include but are not limited to:

- · Conducting meetings with clients to demonstrate work-in-progress on a regular basis.
- · Getting a daily status report to client as well as a weekly report detailing a review of the tasks completed
- Recruiting, Hiring and Train across teams, know every team member's strengths and weaknesses and works with them to ensure a positive outcome.
- Ensure agile principles to ensure successful project deliveries.
- · Analyzing risks, issues and progress to report to both the client and higher management.
- Creating opportunities for the company to gain more business as well as helping the client achieve what he
 needs.
- Encouraging, Arranging, motivating and conducting training and refresher sessions for the resources to get to know new technologies as well as better ways to do common things
- Working closely to mitigate issues including but not limited to leaves, annual leaves planning, curricular activities, annual appraisals and career planning.

DEVELOPMENT LEAD/SCRUM MASTER | CONTOUR SOFTWARE | SEPTEMBER 2014 - PRESENT

- Conducting pre-start meetings with managers.
- · Analyzing the requirements and selecting appropriate resource for the job.
- Ensuring and conducting scrum meetings (daily scrim, planning, review, backlog grooming, and retrospective meetings) to ascertain agile process.
- · Working closely with more than one client via Email, Phone or IMs like Skype etc.
- Working with resources to get client's requirements translated, planned and completed in a timely and accurate way.
- Ensuring that the developer understands and communicates with his client well.
- Ensuring that the client gets timely responses from developer(s) and they delivery exactly what was being expected.

PRINCIPAL SOFTWARE ENGINEER| SHAMS SOFTWARE | APRIL 2011 - APRIL 2014

- · Worked on health care products ranging from CRM to android apps.
- · Requirement gathering and collaboration within team to ensure successful project delivery.
- · Implement CI/CD for smooth product delivery.

SR. SOFTWARE ENGINEER | ALGORITHM CONSULTING | AUGUST 2010 – MARCH 2012

- · Developed various ERP modules of textile industry ranging from import/export to finance.
- · Provided support on multiple projects and accommodate client requirements using agile.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | NET2APPS TECHNOLOGY | JUNE 2007 - AUGUST 2010

- Involved in designing, developing, and installing software solution by following software development lifecycle.
- · Investigates problem areas and provided support.

Education

MASSTERS IN COMPTER SCIENCE | SEPTEMBER 2017 | MUHAMMAD ALI JINNAH UNIVERSITY, KARACHI

BACHELOR'S IN COMPUTER SCIENCE | FEBRUARY 2017 | VIRTUAL UNIVERSITY OF PAKISTAN

MICROSOFT CERTIFICATION | 480 - PROGRAMMING WITH HTML5 WITH JAVASCRIPT AND CSS3 | FEB 14, 2013

MICROSOFT CERTIFICATION | 412-CONFIGURING ADVANCED WINDOWS SERVER 2012 | AUG 20, 2014

Technical Skills & Abilities

- TECHNOLOGIES: Web Development, IOS Development, ERP, CRM, DotNetNuke.
- SERVER-SIDE LANGUAGES: C#, VB.net, C++, Objective C, PHP, Coldfusion, LINQ, SPA.
- · CLIENT-SIDE LANGUAGES: JavaScript, JQuery, JQueryMobile.
- FRAMEWORKS: ASP.Net, Angular, KnockoutJS, MVC, EntityFramework.
- DATABASE: SQL Server, MySQL, SQLITE.
- **DESIGNING**: CSS, HTML5, Bootstrap, Photoshop.
- · OTHERS: JSON, AJAX, XML, XSLT, WebServices, DEVOPS.

Projects

Home builders: warranty management System (www.homeinformationpackages.com). Survey Application for buyers (http://customer-connect.ca), customer insight (http://customerinsight.ca/)

Health Care Projects: Physician Office Solutions, Patient Kiosk, ezWayFinder, EzDictate, E-Learning.

Textile ERP Solution: Inventory Management, Import Bond, GatePass, Finance Module, Procurement Module.

Human Resource: Fippex, Net2Invoice, Net2Survey

Others: 4Tanslation (www.4translation.com)